Adebayo Oluwaseun Community Manager

♀ Lagos, Nigeria

➤ seunbayo83@gmail.com

in linkedin

github

y twitter

A front-end engineer turned community manager with a passion to help people in tech solve problems using technology. I have 4 years building, growing, managing and supporting community values and growth initiatives. I am a community advocate with strong communication skills, creative ideas and evangelistic drive.

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Head of Community, CareerBuddy (Tamborin) ☑

2021 - present

- Managed and grew the online community from 2,000 users to 28,000 users in 2 months
- Track and report on all important growth metrics to help us define and improve on how we serve our community. Implement tactics and strategies to grow the membership of our community.
- Led internal and external community moderators of 9 people in executing the community moderation plan to engage and build a strong community.
- Design and develop activities calendars, build value propositions, Identify pain points that help upskill members of our community
- Create and implement a community building and moderation strategy also coordinating with stakeholders across the company to ensure its effectiveness and provide superior customer service and support to the communities.

Community Manager / Program Manager, CodeClan Africa ☑

2019 - present

CodeClan Nigeria is a community of tech enthusiasts and experts that is focused on mentoring newbies

- Lead the team of community Ambassadors to create localized communities around the world.
- Set up the right operational model to onboard, certify mentors, experts and learners onto the community platform and education programs.
- Work closely with cross-functional teams to implement education programs and promote them across the entire network.
- Manage online communication channels, including Telegram, Twitter, and discord
- Run the community meet-ups session, training and AMA sessions
- Organizing campaigns for community growth engagement, open source programs.

Community Manager & Program Manager, Ingressive4Good + Zuri Training 🖸

- Determine and define program scope and objectives, predict resources needed to reach objectives and manage resources in an effective and efficient manner
- Develop and manage a detailed program schedule and work plan
- Provide project updates on a consistent basis to various stakeholders about strategy, adjustments, and progress
- Analyze, pull data and insights on the health and status of the community and make recommendations for future state engagement models
- Set up the right operational model to onboard, certify mentors, experts and learners onto the community platform and education programs.

February 2021 -

August 2021

Community manager&Program Manager, *Hng* ☑

The HNG internship is a 3-month remote internship designed to find and develop the most talented software developers.

July 2020 -January 2021

- Lead the Marketing, Design, and Product teams to creatively engage the talent community through content, campaigns
- Drive connection and engagement against areas of interest for community
- Moderated and managed an online community of over 13,000 active interns including developing and implementing scalable processes and policies.
- Build, manage and support a team of volunteer Community Champions who will work with you to grow a vibrant and engaging learning community.

Community Manager, *favcode54* ☑

2018 - 2020

Favcode54 is a non-profit initiative that aims to teach and mentor and build the next generation of African software developers. Turning people with no skill into tech geniuses fully equipped to work with tech companies all over the world.

- Developed and execute a social media strategy with metrics and posting schedules
- Help create content for a website, community engagement, and direct outreach
- Support and manage our communities on slack, Twitter and Instagram
- Managed all training programs and cohorts running through the year

CORE COMPETENCIES

• Communication • Collaboration

• Leadership skills • Flexibility and adaptability

• Administrative coordination

• Manage Task Effectively

• Problem-solving skills.

• Organizational skills

• Excellent teambuilders

EDUCATION AND CERTIFICATION

FreeCodeCamp Responsive Web design 🗆 The Web Developer Bootcamp

Product School 🛮 Linkdln

Goole Project Manager certification ☑

level 1 -3

Building with NodeJs

NCE Computer science/Mathematics

TECHNICAL STRENGTHS

Computer Languages

Javascript, VBasic(some knowledge), EmberJs, Java(some knowledge), QBasic, C++(some knowledge)

0ther

Linux, Git, GitHub, AWS